Bilegjargal Jargalsaikhan "Jargal"

Email: bjargal56@gmail.com Mobile: +1-641-451-3892

http://linkedin.com/in/bilegjargal-jargalsaikhan

SUMMARY

Accomplished and technically knowledgeable software developer with 3 years of hands-on experience in software and web development. Implemented several projects through entire development life-cycle for front end and back end modules using Angular, ReactJS and NodeJS technologies. Creative and problem solver, eager to learn new things such as front-end development

Skills

- Programming: Javascript(ES6), HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, MongoDB, Git, NPM, YARN, RESTful API
- Frameworks: ReactJS, Angular, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Agile/SCRUM, Selenium, Jest

EXPERIENCE

Career Note: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a **Master's Degree in Computer Science**(Available for full-time, W-2 employment)

DIGITALWORKS COMPANY

Software Developer

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

- Working on business tool for contract management as a full-stack software developer, contributing specific phases of software developement process, including sprint planning, development, unit testing, review meeting, and deployment.
- Created the feature that generates the contract payment schedule by weekly, monthly or custom time interval and creates an invoice automatically.
- Implemented the new function to add dynamic fields to the document. Resulting in the implementation time for new customer reduced by 30 percent.
- Created a new feature that notes important milestones and generates reports related to payment schedules. Never incur losses due to human mistakes
- Implemented CI/CD(continuous integration/continuous delivery) to my team using cucumber.io-Gherkin syntax. As a result our production delivery became more reliable and bug free.

• ITZONE COMPANY

Software Developer

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Sep 2015 - Mar 2018

- Contributed to ERP system development specially worked in the Supply Chain Management System and Customer Relationship Management System team.
- Created a back-end logic to compute all types of transaction flows over the finance and inventory modules, Resulting improved business process of inventory and finance department workflow by 20 percent. And eradicates faulty transaction occurrence.
- In order to speed up the dynamic report load time, modified SQL queries. As a result dynamic report generating time fastened up to 8 times.
- Worked on client's site and solved many minor and major bugs and problems as a fast phased development. Awarded Customer happiness award in the first quarter of the year.

EDUCATION

 Maharishi University of Management Master of Science in Computer Science; Fairfield, IOWA *Aug. 2018 – In progress*

• Mongolian University of Management Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Aug. 2012 – Jun. 2016